## FREDDY DORDONI

# FULL-STACK DEVELOPER WINE BUYER SOMMELIER

(+ 61) 406 435 297 • fede.dordoni@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Having spent over a decade in all realms of the hospitality world, from owning two successful bars to being a General Manager, my experience is complimented by my extensive Wine and Spirits knowledge, and I am able to offer a unique and vast skillset that can be applied to any facet of the Hospitality, Wine and Tourism industry.

#### **EDUCATION**

2023 – 6 months
UNIVERSITY OF ADELAIDE

Full Stack Flex Program (via edX)

2010 - 2013 AUSTRALIAN PACIFIC COLLEGE

Diploma of Business Management (BSB51107) Certificate IV in Marketing (BSB41307) Certificate III in Business (BSB30107)

#### **AWARDS • ACHIEVEMENTS • CERTIFICATIONS**

#### BRISBANE JUNIOR CHAMBER OF COMMERCE • 2020

Collaborated with head of BJCC during period of mandated business closures due to COVID-19. Devised recovery strategies to adapt: conducted wine education, virtual tastings, and live broadcasts.

### LORD MAYOR MULTICULTURAL MENTORING SCHEME • 2019 to present.

Active member engaging in proactive discussions and adviceon economic development, business stimulation, project planning and progression across numerous industries.

WSET Level 3 in Wine (Distinction with Merit) • 2022 Wine and Spirit Education Trust (WSET) is widely renowned as the authority in Wine education and professional development. Achieved highest grade.

**NATIONAL SWIMMING ACHIEVEMENTS • 2006**Represented Italy in 4 different international competitions
Won Bronze for Italy. 5 Professional titles achieved.

#### **SKILLS**

- STRONG TIME MANGEMENT, PLANNING & PROJECT MANAGEMENT.
- VERSED IN WORKING WITH KPIS AND DEADLINES.
- FULL-STACK DEVELOPER (REACT, JS, MERN, HEROKU, GIT)
- COMFORTABLE IN REPORTING TO SHAREHOLDERS AT ANYTIME.
- EXCELLENT WRITTEN AND VERBAL COMMUNICATION SKILLS.
- SOLID UNDERSTANDING OF MARKET TRENDS, SOCIAL MEDIA CAMPAIGNS, AND INS AND OUTS.
- ABILITY TO NETWORK AND BUILD SOLID RELATIONSHIPS.
- OBJECTIVE PROBLEM SOLVER & MEDIATOR.
- HIGHLY GOAL ORIENTATED AND SELF MOTIVATED.
- EXCELS AT WORKING AUTONOMOUSLY ANDWITH A TEAM.
- STRONG COMPUTER SKILLS.
- FINANCIAL BUDGETING.
- PUBLIC RELATIONS, SOCIAL MEDIA, WEBSITE DESIGN & MARKETING.
- SUPERIOR CUSTOMER SERVICE.
- WELL VERSED IN LANGUAGES (3).
- CONFIDENT PRESENTER AND PUBLIC SPEAKER.
- ADVANCED WINE/SPIRITS KNOWLEDGE.
- PASSSIONATE AND EXTREMELY HARD WORKING.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 2021 - Present

# ASSISTANT CATEGORY MANAGER - Dan Murphy's SENIOR WINE BUYER

Description: in charge of the whole Subscription program across Dan Murphy's (Cellarmaster, Dan Picked). \$11m/year targets met consistently. Procuring and securing the best possible deals to curate monthly Wine packs to over 30,000 subscribers. Working with budgets, KPIs, and strict daily deadlines. Reporting directly to stakeholders and curating a vast array of offering for all different types of subscribers.

#### 2020 - 2021

### WINE MERCHANT – Dan Murphy's (Holland Park)

WINE MERCHANT

Description: helping the store, and the area group, increase wine and spirits knowledge amongst the Team, via a tailored series of bite sized training sessions. Curating the store wine selection, with a focus on premiumization, offering excellent customer service, and lifting the customer shopping experience. Liaising with other Wine Merchants to identify critical area of improvement and see them acted upon.

#### 2018 - 2023

### GRAPE THERAPY WINE & WHISKY BAR & PROUD HENRY GINOTECA

OWNER & SOMMELIER

Description: successfully acquired and revamped two existing businesses. Doubled the profits in the space of six months. Actively working as Owner/ Operator, managing both bars, completing stock take, executing events (from wine and spirit tastings, to sit down private dinners), curating social media for both venues, marketing and financials. Wearing all hats of the hospitality industry.

### 2017 – 2019 RICK SHORES

**SOMMELIER** 

Description: curating an award-winning wine list. Increasing the wine and spirits knowledge amongst the Team via a tailored series of bite sized training sessions. Curating wine and food pairings for degustation menu, with a focus on premiumization, offering. superior customer service and providing a memorable dining experience. Liaising directly with the General Manager and stakeholders to achieve weekly KPIs.

#### **HUGOS MANLY**

RESTAURANT MANAGER (2IC-GM) & SOMMELIER

Description: managing staff and ensuring standards are maintained. Section waiter trainings, rostering duties, cash-closing, function coordination, construction of a sharp and cost-effective wine list, ensuring all GP %'s are met, staff wine trainings and education.

2007 – 2009 EUROFLY S. P. A FLIGHT ATTENDANT

Description: ensuring safety and security of passengers, attending to specific needs, preparing on board facilities, operating Safety and Security Searches of Type A, coordinating on/off board operation. Serving in First Class flights, leading the wine selection and service component.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST.

LinkedIn profile